Guide to the Richard Erdoes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographic Materials, 1952-1999; Series III; 62.25; (70 boxes)
  - Negatives and Contact Prints
    - Binder Pages
      - "Jemez Natl. Mon." [Jemez National Monument], 2 ¼ black and white negatives and contact prints, undated (Box 34, Folder 363)
      - 2 ¼ black and white negatives and contact prints - 38 pages, undated (Box 34, Folder 364-366)
        Page captions: Lame Deer; Winner, S.D.; Acoma, Gallup; Ghost Dance; Rosebud; Sundance; Oohosis; Navajo Sheep Butchering; [Kids at School]; [Fair]
      - Unsorted 2 ¼ black and white negatives and contact prints, undated; 443 negative images (some individual, some in strips or on sheets); 63 pages of contact prints; 22 individual contact prints (Box 35, Folder 367-372)
      - Unsorted 2 ¼ black and white negatives and contact prints, undated; 69 negatives; 49 contact prints (Box 35, Folder 373)
      - Black and white negatives and contact prints, various formats, undated; 23 negative strips; 5 individual negatives; 3 black and white slides; 23 contact print images (Box 35, Folder 374)
  - Transparencies
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Transparencies documenting American Indians and the American West have been digitized and are available through the Beinecke's Digital Library.
    In this subseries, transparencies that Erdoes housed loosely in boxes-- these include both unmounted and mounted transparencies-- have been listed first, in chronological order with undated material following. Transparencies that Erdoes stored in binder pages are then listed. Undated sets of transparencies have been grouped according to subject, with transparencies of American Indian tribes, communities, reservations, and individuals listed first, followed by sets related to American locations, and then European locales.
    Folder titles have been transcribed from Erdoes's original containers, and in instances where Erdoes sub-divided containers, his section labels have been transcribed in a folder note as "Captions." Estimates of the number of individual transparencies and in some cases, slides that were housed with his transparencies, are provided.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Boxes
      - "California - Frisco and L.A. Trip 1955 plus New Mexico, " 2 ¼ color transparencies and 2 ¼ color glass slides, 1955, undated; Circa 127 transparencies, 9 glass slides (Box 36)
      - "Germany 1965," 2 ¼ color transparencies and 2 ¼ color mounted slides, 1965, undated; Circa 411 transparencies, 23 slides (Box 36)
      - "Italy 1965," 2 ¼ color transparencies, 1965, undated; Circa 414 transparencies (Box 36)
      - "Sioux, Cheyennes, Ceremonies," 2 ¼ color transparencies, 1971-1972, undated; Circa 609 transparencies (Box 37)
        Captions: Yuwipi Preparation; Tie Up; Buffalo Ceremony; Sweatbath; Sweatlodge; Dog Feast; Hanbleceya; Peyote in Henry's House; Peyote in Tipi; Sundance; Winner; Wouned Knee; Transport Pole; Crow Dog; Pine Ridge; Rosebud; Issiwun; Cheyenne; Herb Picking; Dances; Eagle Dance
      - "1970/1971 1972 West, Good, Non-Indian, West Best," 2 ¼ color transparencies, 1970-1972, undated; Circa 353 transparencies (Box 37)
      - "Prehistory, Cliffdwellers, Mesa Verde, Anasazi, Precolumb.," 2 ¼ color transparencies, undated; Circa 221 transparencies (Box 38)
        Captions: Pueblo Bonito; Mesa Verde General; Sun Temple; Cliff Palace; Various Ruins; Betatakin; Canyon de Chelly; Scapes; Deserts, Dunes; Farms, Hogans; White House Ruin; Aztec Ruins; Antelope House; Rock Paintings; Kuava Kiva; El Morro, Inscriptions, Ruins, Pictographs; Zuni, Petroglyphs; Acoma; Utah; Nimi; Prehistoric Artifacts; Salmon Ruins; Monument Valley, Navajos and Cattle
      - "West Best Animals, Plants, Fossils," 2 ¼ color transparencies, undated; Circa 191 transparencies (Box 38)
      - "New Jersey Nature, Non Ceremonial Plains Indians," 2 ¼ color transparencies, undated; Circa 544 transparencies (Box 38)
        Captions: School; Give Away; Houses; Ft. Laramie; Tipis; Powwow Day; Rushmore; Buffalo Heads; Crow Fair; Lamedeer; Jerymeat; Beading; Cheyennes; Little Bighorn; Indians in New York; Pictographs; Petroglyphs; Buffalo Jump, Skulls; Pine Ridge; Rosebud; Basketball; Wounded Knee; Sheepherding; Women Striking Tent; Plains Art; BIA; Hokahay; Hungry Wolf
      - "Palisades Zoo, Circus, Botanical Garden," 2 ¼ color transparencies, undated; Circa 68 transparencies (Box 39)
      - "New York and East," 2 ¼ color transparencies, undated; Circa 305 transparencies (Box 39)
      - "New York City," 2 ¼ color transparencies; 1 2 ¼ transparency in plastic mount; 2 ¼ black and white negatives, undated; Circa 364 transparencies (Box 39)
      - "Eastern Travel," 2 ¼ color transparencies, undated; Circa 478 transparencies (Box 39)
      - "Ireland," 2 ¼ color transparencies, undated; Circa 523 transparencies (Box 40)
      - "Austria, France," 2 ¼ color transparencies, undated; Circa 110 transparencies (Box 40)
    - Binder Pages
      - "Acoma," 2 ¼ color transparencies - 20 pages, undated (Box 41, Folder 375-376)
        Captions: Church, Cemetary; Fiesta; People; Santana Antonio; Santana Family; Antonio & Family; Santa & Family; Antonio Family; Streets, Houses; Village; Waterhole; Old Trail, Stairs; Acomita; Landscape
      - "S.W. Pueblo Indians, Ruins," 2 ¼ color transparencies - 33 pages, undated (Box 41, Folder 377-379)
        Captions: Santa Clara Fiesta; San Juan; Mattachines; Hopi Fields, Villa; Piki Making, Eating; Pueblo Crafts, Pottery, People; Taos People, Bread Making, Church; San Ildefonso; Zuni Firefighters, Jewelry Maker, People, Dances, Fiesta, Village; Tarhumara; Apache; Mesa Verde; Chaco Canyon; Petroglyphs; Canyon de Chelly
      - "Sioux," 2 ¼ color transparencies - 30 pages, undated (Box 41, Folder 380-382)
        Captions: B.I.A.; Sundance; Ghost Dance; Sioux People, Wedding; NYC; Winner, S.D.; Peyote; Interiors; Families; Children; Men; Yuwipi; Sweatlodge; Women; Beading
      - "Sioux, Lame Deer, Crow Dog," 2 ¼ color transparencies - 27 pages, undated (Box 41, Folder 383-385)
        Captions: Mt. Rushmore; John Fire Lame Deer; Crow Dog Family; Francine, Henry, Leonard and Colleen [Crow Dog]
      - "Italy 1965 - 1A Loose Color," mounted 2 ¼ transparencies - 1 page, undated (Box 41, Folder 386)
      - Loose sheets - 5 pages, undated (Box 41, Folder 387)
        Captions: Circus, Amusement Park; NYC
  - Slides
    35mm slides that Erdoes created relating to American Indians and the American West have been digitized and are available through the Beinecke's Digital Library. Appraisal occurred at the container level. Images that were not digitized include Erdoes's slides of Ireland, Amsterdam, Florida, and the East Coast.
    The slides in this subseries have been maintained in an arrangement that reflects the physical sequence of materials after rehousing was undertaken to prepare the slides for cold storage. Material in the original containers that Erdoes used to store his slide collection are in many cases housed in multiple boxes due to rehousing. A set of unmounted slides is listed at the end of the subseries.
    This subseries consists of more than 32,000 individual color 35mm slides that Erdoes prepared or obtained between 1975 and 1999. The slide sets contain both original images photographed by Erdoes, as well as reproductions of materials held by museums and libraries. The majority of images relate to Erdoes's American Indian work and his interest in the American West, though sets are present that document trips to other areas of the United States as well as to Ireland and Amsterdam.
    Erdoes originally stored these slides in labeled plastic containers, which he further sub-divided into sets of images described with brief captions. Erdoes occasionally annotated individual slides with identifying information about the subject or location of a slide, but this level of captioning is not consistent across containers or sets. The labels that Erdoes gave to individual containers, as well as the image sets within, are transcribed in the box and folder listing below. Date spans have been estimated for sets, although the majority of individual slides are undated; periods represented from set to set, and from container to container, overlap. Provided dates may also reflect the year when a slide was mounted, rather than the date when the image was captured.
    American Indian peoples that are particularly well represented in Erdoes's slides include the Navajo (Diné), Pueblo, and Lakota, though there are slides that document Cheyenne, Crow, Iroquois (Houdenosaunee), and Muskogee as well. Erdoes recorded the daily life and traditions of many of the communities and families he visited, though he also captured special events, inlcuding ceremonies, spiritual practices and community gatherings, as well as local architecture, arts production, and industry. Image sets related to his work with co-authors (Leonard Crow Dog, Archie Fire Lame Deer, John Fire Lame Deer) and their families are present. Erdoes also documented the physical traces of ancient American Indian civilizations, and seemed particularly interested in petroglyphs, mounds, and archaeological sites. Like his photographic work in other formats, the slides include portraits, scenic and landscape photographs, and photojournalistic work.
    - "Plains Indians, Housing, Landscapes, Personal Pix, Ecology [Plains, Landscapes, Houses, Tipis, Strip Mining / Sioux Housing Scapes]"
      - "Tipi Exterior", 1971-1990, undated; 68 slides (Box 42)
      - "Tipi Interior", 1975, undated; 22 slides (Box 42)
      - "Putting up of Tipis", 1975-1983, undated; 25 slides (Box 42)
      - "Pine Ridge Landscape", 1971-1977, undated; 60 slides (Box 42)
      - "Mission South Dakota", 1970, undated; 31 slides (Box 42)
      - "Tipi Double Exposure", 1976, undated; 30 slides (Box 42)
      - "Rosebud Landscape", 1969-1981, undated; 50 slides (Box 42)
      - "Pine Ridge Winter", 1970, undated; 14 slides (Box 42)
      - "Graves", 1970-1975, undated; 29 slides (Box 42)
      - "Ecology", 1971-1977, undated; 38 slides (Box 42)
      - "Strip Mining", 1970-1975, undated; 18 slides (Box 42)
      - "Sioux Pottery – Rapid City", undated; 9 slides (Box 42)
      - "Anadarko Bldgs", 1971-1972, undated; 50 slides (Box 42)
      - "Sunset Rosebud", 1970-1979, undated; 29 slides (Box 42)
      - "Roadgang Sunsets", undated; 20 slides (Box 42)
      - "Rosebud Housing", 1970-1993, undated; 62 slides (Box 42)
      - "Repronaz Experiment", 1973, undated; 24 slides (Box 42)
      - "Tribal Council", 1975-1981, undated; 34 slides (Box 42)
    - "Navajo People, Riders, Sheep Herders, Sand Painters, Working People, Etc".
      - "Women at Work, Police, Gas Station, Etc.", 1977, undated; 25 slides (Box 43)
      - "Navajo Women", 1962-1991, undated; 16 slides (Box 43)
      - "Navajo Men Working", 1977, undated; 9 slides (Box 43)
      - "Navajo Men", 1974-1979, undated; 30 slides (Box 43)
      - "Boy Riders I", 1975, undated; 24 slides (Box 43)
      - "Navajo Children", 1962-1979; 12 slides (Box 43)
      - "Girls", 1975-1977, undated; 22 slides (Box 43)
      - "Boys", 1975-1977, undated; 19 slides (Box 43)
      - "Sheep Herder Male", 1977-1991, undated; 11 slides (Box 43)
      - "Girl Riders II", 1977, undated; 20 slides (Box 43)
      - "Girl Riders I", 1977, undated; 19 slides (Box 43)
      - "Boy Rider II", 1977, undated; 30 slides (Box 43)
      - "Sheep Butchering", 1993, undated; 20 slides (Box 43)
      - "Sheep Herding, Canyon De Chelley, Close Up", 1969-1979, undated; 11 slides (Box 43)
      - "Sheep Herding, Canyon De Chelley, Long", 1969-1979, undated; 26 slides (Box 43)
      - "Sheep Herding Female", 1976-1979, undated; 15 slides (Box 43)
      - "Silversmiths Male-Female", 1977, undated; 27 slides (Box 43)
      - "People on Wagon", 1964-1977, undated; 16 slides (Box 43)
      - "Cattle Boys Horse Roping", 1975-1977, undated; 17 slides (Box 43)
      - "Sheep Herding General Pens", 1968-1977, undated; 30 slides (Box 43)
      - "Navajo Electrician's Telephone", 1977; 21 slides (Box 43)
      - "Modern Sand Painting", 1977, undated; 26 slides (Box 43)
      - "Sand Painting II", 1977-1979, undated; 18 slides (Box 43)
      - "Sand Painter and Sand Painting", 1977-1979, undated; 25 slides (Box 43)
    - "Mexico 1980. Yucatan"
      - "Haciendas, Hotels, Flowers", 1980, undated; 30 slides (Box 43)
      - "Bullfight, Cemeteries", 1980, undated; 36 slides (Box 43)
      - "Merida Architecture", 1980, undated; 41 slides (Box 43)
      - "Merida, Mostly People, Cemeteries", 1980, undated; 38 slides (Box 43)
      - "Chichen-Itza", 1980, undated; 34 slides (Box 44)
      - "Chichen-Itza", 1980, undated; 37 slides (Box 44)
      - "Uxmal", 1980, undated; 28 slides (Box 44)
      - "Uxmal, Pyramid and My Old Pix", 1980, undated; 22 slides (Box 44)
      - "Lacandones, Houses, Hermosa People", 1980, undated; 29 slides (Box 44)
      - "Mayan Villagers", 1980, undated; 27 slides (Box 44)
      - "Mayan House, Kaba, Labna", 1980, undated; 39 slides (Box 44)
      - "Chichenitza, Caracol, and area", 1980, undated; 34 slides (Box 44)
      - "Palenque, Small Temples", 1980, undated; 25 slides (Box 44)
      - "Palenque, Palacio, Hieroglyphs", 1980, undated; 33 slides (Box 44)
      - "Palenque", 1980, undated; 23 slides (Box 44)
      - "Mayan House, Chichen-Itza, Family", 1980, undated; 23 slides (Box 44)
      - "Chamulas, Weaver, Voladores", 1980, undated; 23 slides (Box 44)
      - "Chiapas, Highlands", 1980, undated; 23 slides (Box 44)
      - "Tulum, Koba Hotel", 1980, undated; 28 slides (Box 44)
      - "Villahermosa, La Venta", 1980, undated; 26 slides (Box 44)
      - "San Cristóbal Market", 1980, undated; 37 slides (Box 44)
      - "San Cristóbal Market", 1980, undated; 29 slides (Box 44)
      - "San Cristóbal Market", 1980, undated; 23 slides (Box 44)
      - "San Cristóbal City", 1980, undated; 31 slides (Box 44)
    - "Plains Indian History I"
      - "Cherokee Seminole", 1974-1976, undated; 38 slides (Box 44)
      - "Virginia. de Bry (as in Thomas de Bry)", 1976-1983, undated; 41 slides (Box 44)
      - "Early East Coast Wars", 1976-1980, undated; 41 slides (Box 44)
      - "17th & 18th Century", 1974-1978, undated; 42 slides (Box 44)
      - "Villages Tipis", 1975-1976, undated; 19 slides (Box 45)
      - "Early Plains Life", 1970-1976, undated; 40 slides (Box 45)
      - "Mandan Arikiara, Skiki-Pawnee", 1975-1976, undated; 40 slides (Box 45)
      - "Wichita, Marquette", 1976, undated; 42 slides (Box 45)
      - "White Hunters Beaver", 1976-1978, undated; 22 slides (Box 45)
      - "Buffalo Indians Hunting", 1976-1985, undated; 32 slides (Box 45)
      - "Horses, Riders, Travois", 1971-1980, undated; 39 slides (Box 45)
      - "Bullboats Crossings", 1971-1976, undated; 22 slides (Box 45)
      - "Indians vs. Trappers, Cowboys Settlers", 1976-1983, undated; 38 slides (Box 45)
      - "Early Plains Wars, Gratian, Sully, Mankato, Etc.", 1976, undated; 39 slides (Box 45)
      - "Treaty Making", 1970-1976, undated; 39 slides (Box 45)
      - "Rituals, Shaman Kitpoo", 1971-1988, undated; 36 slides (Box 45)
      - "Custer Portraits", 1976-1978, undated; 30 slides (Box 45)
      - "Various Fights, Sand Creek, Black Hawk, Etc.", 1976, undated; 39 slides (Box 45)
      - "Washita, Early Custer", 1976, undated; 28 slides (Box 45)
      - "Fetterman, Bozeman, Wagon Box, R.R. Fight", 1976, undated; 40 slides (Box 45)
      - "Little Big Horn B&W", 1976, undated; 39 slides (Box 45)
      - "Little Big Horn, Rosebud Color", 1975-1976, undated; 35 slides (Box 45)
      - "Schreyvogel, Remington, Etc.", 1976-1985, undated; 35 slides (Box 45)
      - "Custer Scenes", 1976, undated; 29 slides (Box 45)
    - "Plains Indian History II"
      - "Wounded Knee", 1976, undated; 32 slides (Box 45)
      - "Ghost Dance", 1975-1976, undated; 33 slides (Box 45)
      - "Nez Perce War", 1976-1978, undated; 35 slides (Box 45)
      - "Late Indian Wars", 1976, undated; 40 slides (Box 45)
      - "Kickapoo Medicine Show", 1983, undated; 21 slides (Box 46)
      - "Early Reservation Life", 1976, undated; 22 slides (Box 46)
      - "Indian-White Relations", 1976, n.d; 37 slides (Box 46)
      - "Wounded Knee, Crazy Horse", 1976, n.d; 33 slides (Box 46)
      - "Generals Howard, Crook, Etc.", 1976, n.d; 38 slides (Box 46)
      - "Generals Sherman, Miles, Sheriden", 1976, n.d; 24 slides (Box 46)
      - "Chiefs, Non-Sioux", 1976-1993, n.d; 26 slides (Box 46)
      - "Chiefs, Sioux", 1975-1993, undated; 37 slides (Box 46)
      - "Pollution, Power Plants", 1967-1985, undated; 39 slides (Box 46)
      - "Strip Mining, Exploitation, Ecology", 1975-1986, undated; 16 slides (Box 46)
      - "Early Reservation Life", 1976, undated; 34 slides (Box 46)
      - "Forts", 1976, undated; 22 slides (Box 46)
      - "Indian Steps, Museum Penna, Games", 1986, undated; 8 slides (Box 46)
      - "Modern Maps", 1976, undated; 15 slides (Box 46)
      - "19th Century Maps", 1976-1983, undated; 40 slides (Box 46)
      - "18th Century Maps", 1976-1983, undated; 40 slides (Box 46)
      - "Indian Authors, Bumper Stickers", undated; 24 slides (Box 46)
      - "Eastman Schoolcraft", 1987; 29 slides (Box 46)
      - "Soldiers", 1976; 8 slides (Box 46)
      - "Newspaper Headlines", 1970-1984, undated; 26 slides (Box 46)
    - "Antonios, Acoma, N.M".
      - "Santana House Outdoors", 1975-1993, undated; 21 slides (Box 46)
      - "Santana's Family 1955-1972", undated; 6 slides (Box 46)
      - "Joe and Santana", 1975, undated; 14 slides (Box 46)
      - "Santana 1952-1972", 1975-1992, undated; 15 slides (Box 46)
      - "Antonio Family Indoors", 1975, undated; 17 slides (Box 46)
      - "Charles Roger Boys", 1975, undated; 26 slides (Box 46)
      - "Josie & K.K.", 1975, undated; 17 slides (Box 46)
      - "Santana after 1975", 1975-1976, undated; 27 slides (Box 46)
      - "Pottery Making Medium", 1975, undated; 32 slides (Box 46)
      - "Pottery Making Long", 1975, undated; 22 slides (Box 46)
      - "Santana Making Pottery Long", undated; 21 slides (Box 46)
      - "Santana Pottery Making 1964", undated; 20 slides (Box 46)
      - "Pottery Firing Night & Day", undated; 19 slides (Box 46)
      - "Pottery Firing Day", 1975, undated; 33 slides (Box 47)
      - "Pottery Making Extreme Close Up", 1975, undated; 23 slides (Box 47)
      - "Pottery Making Close Up", 1975, undated; 32 slides (Box 47)
      - "Chili Grinding Close Up", 1975, undated; 18 slides (Box 47)
      - "Chili Grinding", 1975, undated; 16 slides (Box 47)
      - "Pottery Toys Owls", undated; 18 slides (Box 47)
      - "Pottery Grinding", 1975, undated; 16 slides (Box 47)
      - "Santana at Water Hole", 1975, undated; 31 slides (Box 47)
      - "Bread Making Close Up", 1975, undated; 26 slides (Box 47)
      - "Bread Making Medium", 1975, undated; 20 slides (Box 47)
      - "Bread Making Long", 1975-1976, undated; 13 slides (Box 47)
    - "Navajo Ecology History, Fair School Industry, Miccosukee, Mohawk, NYC Comm House"
      - "Chinle School Medium- Close Up", 1975-1976, undated; 24 slides (Box 47)
      - "Chinle School Long Tohatchie School", 1975-1977, undated; 30 slides (Box 47)
      - "Chinle School Long", 1975-1977, undated; 28 slides (Box 47)
      - "Stork Cemet[e]ry Ft Defiance", 1977, undated; 21 slides (Box 47)
      - "School Playing Field", 1977, undated; 26 slides (Box 47)
      - "Navajo History", 1976-1977, undated; 31 slides (Box 47)
      - "Ecology Protests", 1976-1978, undated; 30 slides (Box 47)
      - "Chinle School Close Up", 1972-1976, undated; 28 slides (Box 47)
      - "Industry Navajo", 1957-1972, undated; 21 slides (Box 47)
      - "Beauty Queens Navajo", 1975, undated; 21 slides (Box 47)
      - "Rodeo and Camp", 1962-1976; 28 slides (Box 47)
      - "Navajo Fair 1964", 1977, undated; 26 slides (Box 47)
      - "Miccosukee Tom Tiger", 1973, undated; 29 slides (Box 47)
      - "Tom Tiger's Place", 1973, undated; 23 slides (Box 47)
      - "Two Women Camp", undated; 26 slides (Box 47)
      - "Miccosukee Kids", undated; 24 slides (Box 47)
      - "Mohawk Lacrosse", undated; 33 slides (Box 47)
      - "Jim Tiger's Place", undated; 25 slides (Box 48)
      - "Miccosukee School Offices", undated; 23 slides (Box 48)
      - "Tamiami Canal Chickees", undated; 23 slides (Box 48)
      - "NYC Indian Comm. Center", undated; 31 slides (Box 48)
      - "Akwesasne", 1975, undated; 24 slides (Box 48)
      - Unlabeled, undated; 38 slides (Box 48)
      - Unlabeled #2, undated; 30 slides (Box 48)
    - "Anasazi Ruins, Arizona, Colorado, included: Tonto, Montezuma, Mesa Verde, Aztec"
      - "Antelope House Canyon De Chelly", 1977, undated; 21 slides (Box 48)
      - "White House Ruin Close Up", 1977, undated; 18 slides (Box 48)
      - "White House Ruin Medium Long and Fall", 1977, undated; 21 slides (Box 48)
      - "White House Ruin, Long Canyon De Chelly", 1977, undated; 22 slides (Box 48)
      - "Hovenweep, Jackie's Dig", 1980, undated; 26 slides (Box 48)
      - "Keetseel Betatakin", 1977-1980, undated; 26 slides (Box 48)
      - "Canyon Chelly Ruins 1991", 1991, undated; 21 slides (Box 48)
      - "Canyo[n] De Chelly. Ruins", 1977-1988, undated; 29 slides (Box 48)
      - "Gila Cliffs 1990", 1977-1990, undated; 29 slides (Box 48)
      - "Montezuma's Well Toozigoot", 1977-1980, undated; 16 slides (Box 48)
      - "Montezuma's Castle & Flagstaff Interiors", 1979-1985, undated; 26 slides (Box 48)
      - "Montezuma's Castle Dolores", 1979-1991, undated; 18 slides (Box 48)
      - "Gala Cliffs NM 1990/ Aztec 91", 1991; 31 slides (Box 48)
      - "Walnut Canyon Wupatki", 1979-1985, undated; 25 slides (Box 48)
      - "Ball Court and Monument Valley Ruins", 1975-1991, undated; 15 slides (Box 48)
      - "Tonto Cave Ruin", 1985; 25 slides (Box 48)
      - "Aztec Ruin Kiva", undated; 25 slides (Box 48)
      - "Aztec Ruin Close Up", 1977-1991, undated; 23 slides (Box 48)
      - "Aztec Ruin Medium", 1976, undated; 24 slides (Box 48)
      - "Aztec Ruin Colorado Long", undated; 22 slides (Box 48)
      - "Mesa Verde Ruins", 1983-1991, undated; 18 slides (Box 49)
      - "Mesa Verde Various Ruins", 1980-1991, undated; 32 slides (Box 49)
      - "Mesa Verde Cliff Palace", 1991, undated; 24 slides (Box 49)
      - "Mesa Verde Colo. Spruce Tree House", 1991, undated; 12 slides (Box 49)
    - "Acoma, Houses, Streets, Scapes"
      - "Stairs", 1975, undated; 5 slides (Box 49)
      - "Approach", 1975, 1981, undated; 25 slides (Box 49)
      - "Acoma Landscapes, Approaches", 1975, 1981, undated; 21 slides (Box 49)
      - "Katzimo Enchanted Mesa", 1975-1981, undated; 22 slides (Box 49)
      - "Ladders", 1975, undated; 20 slides (Box 49)
      - "Old Houses", 1975-1977; 13 slides (Box 49)
      - "Acoma Old Houses", 1975-1977, undated; 11 slides (Box 49)
      - "Acoma Birdseye View", 1975, undated; 20 slides (Box 49)
      - "Water Hole", 1975; 4 slides (Box 49)
      - "Steeple Guards", 1975, undated; 19 slides (Box 49)
      - "Acoma Church", 1975-1981, undated; 25 slides (Box 49)
      - "Acoma Streets", 1975-1977, undated; 21 slides (Box 49)
      - "Midnight Mass", 1975, undated; 10 slides (Box 49)
      - "Fiesta", 1975-1985, undated; 25 slides (Box 49)
      - "Acoma People", 1975-1976, undated; 27 slides (Box 49)
      - "Sheep Camp", 1975, undated; 21 slides (Box 49)
      - "Sheep Camp", 1975, undated; 18 slides (Box 49)
      - "Pottery Display", undated; 9 slides (Box 49)
      - "Acoma Historical", 1973, undated; 3 slides (Box 49)
      - "Grant's Lava Flow", 1975-1976, undated; 16 slides (Box 49)
      - "Mildred's Place", 1975; 13 slides (Box 49)
      - "McCarty's", undated; 2 slides (Box 49)